<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Geophysics on All About Helin Henstridge</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/tags/geophysics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Geophysics on All About Helin Henstridge</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/tags/geophysics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Education</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/education/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/education/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;education&#34;&gt;Education&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;phd-in-earth-science---university-of-california-santa-barbara&#34;&gt;PhD in Earth Science - University of California, Santa Barbara&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2025 - Present&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.geol.ucsb.edu/&#34;&gt;Program Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am currently a first-year graduate student in the Earth Science department at UCSB. My research focuses on using deep learning and geophysical datasets to predict localized critical mineral deposits in the conterminous United States.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;bachelors-of-science-in-physics-biophysics---university-of-california-san-diego&#34;&gt;Bachelors of Science in Physics-Biophysics - University of California, San Diego&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;2021 - 2025&lt;/em&gt;&lt;br&gt;&#xA;GPA: 3.615 / 4.0&lt;br&gt;&#xA;&lt;a href=&#34;https://physics.ucsd.edu/&#34;&gt;Program Link&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Minor in Mathematics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coursework experience in physics, math, biology, chemistry, and other general education courses&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hands-on research experience in neurophysics, materials physics, and condensed physics&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/research/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h1 id=&#34;undergraduate-research&#34;&gt;Undergraduate Research&lt;/h1&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;neurophysics---dr-william-kristan-ucsd&#34;&gt;Neurophysics - Dr. William Kristan, UCSD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I designed and executed my own research experiment to measure phototaxis of planarians temporally and spatially, including how their replication affects their phototaxis. I did this by creating varying light gradients for planarians; establishing a system of computers, computer programs, a handheld projector, camera, and microscope; utilizing microscopy techniques to record the planarians movement and analyze their phototaxis after experimentation.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;materials-physics---dr-olivia-graeve-ucsd&#34;&gt;Materials Physics - Dr. Olivia Graeve, UCSD&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I collaborated in writing a literature review about optical, magnetic, and electrical properties of ceramic metal oxides by reading, summarizing and articulating to peers and supervisors the relevant conclusions and topics of relevant papers. I also worked on the creation of a database of properties of carbide materials for aerospace purposes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
